it can be tough to find the right
weightlifting belt for your workouts but
if you're looking for one that provides
a high level of support without reducing
your Mobility one of my personal
favorites is the iron B 7 mm leather
lifting belt this belt requires zero
break-in period and it's tapered in the
front so it's going to allow you to say
pretty mobile within your hips I think
youall know what time it is it's time
for a full
[Music]
review
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbin garage gym and for today's
video I'm going to be breaking down the
iron bull 7 mm leather lifting belt in
this video today I'm going to tell you
everything there is to know about this
belt from the price to some pros and
cons and then of course who should or
maybe should not make this purchase but
before I do that just want to make sure
y'all know that we've reviewed a lot of
other lifting belts on Barb and.com and
we went ahead and came up with our own
best list so if you want to check that
out out all you going to do is search
barbend best weightlifting belt it's
going to pull right up for you you can
find out for yourself which ones we like
the
best okay so before I start talking
about you know what I really like about
this belt I've done this in previous
videos but I still just want to touch on
the benefits of lifting belts and kind
of you know which ones to Target right
so there's a lot of different styles
really it boils down to your personal
preference especially when it comes to
your style of lifting right so first of
all you know lifting belts they're going
to help create intraabdominal pressure
that way you can brace harder and it's
going to help you you know lift heavier
weight but also reduce you know the
chances of injury because you definitely
don't want to get hurt now this is a
fully leather belt obviously there's you
know nylon belts there's hybrid belts
there's neoprene belts it's a whole lot
out there and they vary in thickness as
well so 13 mm thick a fully leather belt
really only going to want to use that
for squatting and deadlifting you're
going to be really stiff and and it's
just not going to be able to use across
you know multiple lifts like you know
for Olympic weightlifting and Crossfit
for example for those you know most
people tend to go after a nylon belt
because you know they're still going to
provide a high level of support but
you're really able to stay mobile and
that's something that you need during
those specific style of lifts now with a
7 mm belt like this especially one
that's tapered in the front you're kind
of getting the Best of Both Worlds
that's what I really like about this
belt so you're going to be able to have
you know a high level of support as I
mention
but you know without the you know
leather digging into your ribs and
everything you can bend at your waist
and do a whole lot more than you could
with a 4-in belt you all the way around
also really like how there's zero
Breakin with this belt once you get it
out of the box it's ready to go you know
a lot of times with leather belts
they're stiff I mean that's the point of
them but you still have to break them in
and kind of get comfortable and
everything that's not the case here I
really like the suede inside right here
it's a little bit of a moisture wicking
and it's also just kind of comfortable
on your skin in now I really don't think
there's a a con at all with this belt it
really as I mentioned a second ago it's
just personal preference on what you're
looking for for your specific lifting
style okay so this is kind of like a you
know hybrid belt sort of I know hybrid
usually means you know leather with you
know nylon on the outside kind of two
belts in one when I say hybrid right
here it means you can use it for
powerlifting and for you know CrossFit
Olympic style weightlifting you could
now it not it might not be the best for
that though right so it's all just
personal preference do you want a
thicker belt do you want just a fully
you know nylon belt like I said it's
just personal preference this is a
really solid belt I don't really think
you can go wrong with
[Music]
it so the ironbull 7 mm leather lifting
belt it's going to cost you right around
60 bucks this is a pretty sweet deal in
my opinion and it's average you know
across the market with similar belts now
when you compare it to a nylon belt it's
going to cost you more more all right so
iron blls 6 in reinforced it's a nylon
belt that's going to cost you about 35
bucks while they're 10 mm premium belt
it's about $175 so in my opinion you
know you're getting Best of Both Worlds
with those belts this is kind of you
know hybrid I guess and 60 bucks I don't
think you can go wrong with that
whatsoever all right so I've said it a
couple times and as the name suggests
this is a fully leather belt and it's 7
mm thick so it's going to be really nice
for your core support and give you a
bunch of extra stability so I really
like this suede interior it's not like
it's you know uncommon or anything it's
just really nice you know it's
comfortable on your skin it's also going
to be a little bit moisture wicking
which is a very nice thing especially if
you sweat a lot now you do have this
dual prong steel Buckle right here it's
going to be really nice you know it fits
in all these obviously and it it's just
really secure especially with this extra
Loop right here belt's not going to go
anywhere whenever you go to put it on
and whenever you put it on you know
speaking of remember you want it to go
around your belly button and same thing
goes whenever you go to do your sizing
so remember comes from small to double
XL whenever you had to measure yourself
measure around your belly button because
that's where it goes right so problem a
lot of people have with lifting belts is
they don't wear them the right way you
have all these you know adjustments
these holes whatever you want to call
them people love you know ratcheting it
in making it super tight that's really
not the way to go what you want to do is
find a nice comfortable spot where you
can still take your thumb and squeeze it
in that way whenever you go to breathe
you can really expand your stomach like
and then that way you can you know get
that intraabdominal pressure and really
brace up against the belt and as you can
see you know this is 4 in in the back
and it tapers down to two right here I
really like that I love wearing belts
like this whenever I go to squat that
way I'm really able to get into depth
and it's not going to dig into my ribs
make it uncomfortable or anything like
that so yeah 60 bucks for this
everything that it entails pretty solid
I think this is a great belt for any
body who's looking for one that is
certified across multiple federations I
also think this is great for
powerlifting because you do have that
fully leather build and it's 7 mm thick
however also think it's great for
anybody who wants you know a belt that
allows them to stay pretty you know
mobile and explosive for Olympic
weightlifting and Crossfit this is
actually our favorite belt for Olympic
weightlifting and that's because of that
taper design like I said it's going to
allow you to stay Mobile in your hips
and and bend and everything and that's
definitely something that you want with
those lifts but you're not going to be
sacrificing any type of stability
whatsoever only reason my opinion I
guess there's it's it's just personal
preference why you wouldn't want to buy
this belt right do you want more
stability do you want you know a nylon
build for even more Mobility whenever
you're working out so like I said it
really just boils down to personal
preference that's all I got for y'all
today on the iron bull 7 mm leather
weightlifting belt this belt is is great
for powerlifting because it is fully
leather it does have that 7 mm thickness
but you know it's also great for Olympic
weightlifting because it is tapered in
the front and allows you to stay pretty
mobile thanks for watching y'all I hope
this video was helpful and I was able to
tell you everything there is to know
about this belt as always stay posted
for my next video but for now head over
to barb. comom leave a full written
article about this belt that I think you
should go and check out all you got to
do is search barbend Iron bull 7 mm
leather lifting belt review the article
is going to pull right up for for you
you can go over every single thing we
talked about here today catch youall
next
[Music]
time
f